What's it gonna be, Angelina?
It was Grogan, the filthiest, dirtiest..
Dumbest excuse for a man
west of the Missouri River.
You can die two ways, Angel:
Quick like the tongue
of a snake...
or slower than the molasses
in January.
But it was October.
I'll kill ya, goddamn it, if
it was the Fourth of July.
Where is it?
Get over there.
I told him to get out,
now that he had what he came for.
Not quite, Angel.
Take 'em off. Do it.
Come on!
That was the end of Grogan,
the man who killed my father...
raped and murdered my sister...
burned my ranch, shot my dog...
and stole my Bible!
But if there was
one law of the West...
bastards had brothers...
Who seemed to ride forever,
But suddenly there he was,
my beloved /Jessie.
He was the one man I trusted.
The only man.
My heart leapt as I
watched him ride near.
I could barely wait to feel
the warmth of his touch.
At the moment
his lips met mine...
I knew that we would
never again be apart.
I knew then that we would spend
the rest of our lives together.
Forever.
Oh, God, that's good.
The... end.
Ooh.
Oh.
I finished, sweetheart.
You wanna celebrate, hmm?
So do I.
“Romeo, Romeo,
where art thou, Romeo?”
There. Hey,
it's Bumble Bee, kiddo.
Just so you know,
I spare no expense when I celebrate.
Here's lookin' at you, Jessie...
whoever you are.
Are you finished?
Thank you.
Oh, come here, Romeo.
Yeah.
Hello?
Huh. Oh, my God.
Romeo, is that the time?
Gloria! I'm gonna be late.
- Hi.
- Oh, hi, pumpkin.
Mrs. Irwin, why won't you
take the elevator?
Oh, pumpkin, I never get
into an elevator alone.
You know, rapists.
Where are you running off to?
Oh, I've gotta get
to my publisher's.
By the way, pumpkin, the mailman
couldn't fit this into your box...
so I told him
I'd give it to you.
That's some love letter.
Mrs. Irwin, you're a tease.
I know, but I keep
hoping for you, pumpkin.
Hey, lady, how about a monkey
for your little nephew?
I'll give it to you for $10.
Really great deal.
- Oh, no, I don't-
- It's really nice.
Your boyfriend'll love it.
It's kind of kinky. Come on.
Nine dollars.
Eight dollars, bottom line.
Thank you, but I really
don't need a monkey.
Oh, but, lady, it's kind of cute.
Hey, that's Miss Wilder's apartment.
Can I help you?
Excuse me.
Get away from that door!
What's this?
Wimp, wimp.
Loser, loser.
Major loser.
Too angry, too vague.
Too desperate.
God, too happy!
Oh, look at this guy.
Mr. Mondo-dizmo.
I actually used to date him.
Total sleaze bucket.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Hold everything.
Get a load of this character.
- Now, what about him?
- No. He's-
He's just not-
Who? Jessie?
Maybe it's silly...
but I know that there is
somebody out there for me.
Oh, yeah? Where?
Certainly not here.
Gloria, why do we always have to have
this same conversation?
Because I like you, Joan,
and I hate to see you all alone...
waiting for somebody
who's not gonna show up.
Okay, Gloria.
Here it is.
Mmm.
Read it and weep.
I always do.
- I'll call you, okay?
- Come on. Don't leave.
- Have another grasshopper.
- I can't.
Come on, come on. Stay.
I'm your publisher. I'm ordering you to.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I even dragged you
to this place.
I just want you to get out.
I know how hard you've been working.
I know you're upset
about your sister.
Come on. How is she?
Have you heard from her?
Elaine? I spoke to her
last week.
She's still in Colombia.
Have they... found
her husband's body yet?
Just the one piece.
You know what's really creepy?
I got this package from
Eduardo, from Colombia.
Mm-hmm.
Must've been mailed
just before he-
Mmm. God.
Can you imagine how awful-
having your husband murdered?
Well, how is she holding up?
Oh, she'll be fine.
Elaine always... manages.
Hey, Ira.
The kid's here with the broad.
They're taking her
out to the boat.
Look at these snappers, will ya?
We should've just
rifled her room.
Ralph, how many times do I have
to tell you? It's not in the country.
Well, this kidnapping stuff
makes me real nervous.
It's a piss-poor idea.
It's nothing but trouble.
Look, we've stolen enough
of these antique trinkets...
to keep us living comfortably
for the rest of our lives.
Let's kiss off
this third-world toilet.
One last big one. Trust me, Ralph.
Trust me. Whoa!
Did you see that, Ralph? That ugly,
striped son of a bitch down there.
Somebody's gonna get killed, and you're
farting around with prehistoric animals.
Come on, Ira.
Let's forget this one.
I got a real bad feeling
about it. Real bad.
Will you stop worrying?
Have I ever hurt you?
I will never hurt you.
I can't hurt you.
We got the same blood.
We're not two people.
We are one person.
Would I hurt me?
Look at those snappers, Ralph.
Oh! Oh! Oh, Romeo!
Oh, baby! Oh!
- Hello?
- Hello, Joan? Joan!
- Can you hear me?
- Elaine, I can't talk right now.
Listen to me.
Listen very carefully.
- I'm in trouble.
- Elaine, please.
- Joanie, I am in real trouble.
- What's the matter?
Has any mail been forwarded to you with
Eduardo's handwriting on it?
- Any big envelope?
- Yes.
Oh, honey!
See if there's some kind...
of treasure map inside.
It says, uh, “El Corazon.”
I need you to bring that map
to me in Colombia.
Colombia?
My God, what kind
of trouble are you in?
Joanie, please!
Get to the Hotel Cartagena
in Cartagena.
When you arrive,
call this number:
64-58-24.
- Are you writing this down?
- Yes.
And remember,
you mustn't tell anybody.
Elaine, I can't go to Colombia.
Joanie!
They'll cut me.
They'll hurt me.
Colombia? Do you have any idea
what it's like in Colombia?
I do. Your books do very well
in these macho countries.
They have jungles there, Joanie.
Insects the size of sanitation trucks,
revolutionaries.
- Have you had your shots?
- Shots? What shots?
See, you're completely
unprepared. Wait a minute. Just hold on.
Would you tell me what's going on?
Why are you doing this?
Elaine is in some trouble.
She has a little
domestic problem.
Domestic problem?
Elaine's last domestic problem...
was finding her husband
cut into small pieces.
I'm not gonna let you do this.
You cannot go!
Here's Romeo. Now, I
want you to promise me...
To feed him and hold him
at least once a day.
You're gonna need something
stronger than that.
Listen to me.
You get bus sick...
seasick, plane sick, train sick.
You practically
puke riding on the
escalator at Bloomingdale's,
for God's sake!
Well, a lot of people get sick
in department stores.
Joanie, please don't go.
You're not up to this, Joan,
and you know it.
I know.
But she's my sister.
I'll feed him,
but I'm not picking him up.
You're...
crazy!
The plane from New York,
has it arrived yet?
- The “areo” “arrivo” aquí?
- No comprendo.
Uh, i-i-is this the bus
to Cartagena?
- ¿Qué?
- Oh.
- Uh, Carta-
- Cartagena.
Oh. Oh, you speak English.
Good. Can you tell me,
is this bus going to...
Cartagena?
Yes. Cartagena.
Great. Thank you.
Uh, okay.
Uh-
Oh, thank you.
Huh?
Hey, you're on the wrong bus!
Hey! Miss Wilder!
She got on the wrong bus.
This is terrible.
Oh...
My God.
Excuse me.
Uh-
Excuse, uh-Excuse me.
Oh! Uh-
I'm-I'm-I'm very sorry.
- I'm really sorry.
- Estúpida!
I'm sorry to-to bother you.
Uh, can you tell me
what time we get to Cartagena?
- ¿Qué?
- Is this the bus to Cartagena?
- I need to get to Cartagena-
What are we gonna do now?
Where's my suitcase?
You don't have to walk.
Another bus will come along.
What?
They know nothing.
They are peasants.
Another bus? Really?
Of course.
There are schedules
to be maintained...
even in Colombia.
- What?
- The purse.
What are you-
Jo
Oh, my God!
What the hell?
Jesus Christ!
What the hell happened
to my birds?
Son of a bitch!
Hi.
Oh.
- ¡Vamos!
- Oh, no. Talk about breaks.
Don't I know you?
No comprendo.
You are American.
Amer/canes.
I spit on 'em.
I hate Americanos!
They're ‶scumoʺ!
- Scum!
- Hmm.
You must be French.
Well, honey, looks like we're gonna have
to wait just a little longer, huh?
Shit!
Excuse me. Could you please tell me
how to get to a telephone?
No, lady. I don't have any idea.
I'm sorry.
It's very important
that I get one.
Well, we've all got
our problems today, don't we?
Can you tell me
where the nearest town is?
- How about Miami?
- Will there be another bus?
This is it.
You got rush hour.
I, uh-I have to get
to Cartagena.
Cartagena?
Angel, you are hell
and gone from Cartagena.
Cartagena's over there
on the coast.
- But they told me this bus-
- Who told you that?
- That man that... That nice man
who pulled a gun on you. Uh-huh.
What else did he tell you?
- Please, I need your help.
- That's my new career, huh?
- It's very-
- Lady-Lady...
half a year's work just flew south
for the winter, all right?
My jeep is totaled.
In five minutes,
everything I own in the
world's gonna be wet,
so can you lighten up?
- I really don't have the time.
- I'll pay you.
You don't understand. It's a matter of life
and death. If I don't get to my sis-
- How much?
- Fifty dollars?
Oh, shit.
Well, you said you just lost
everything you owned.
- Not my sense of humor.
- Well, I'll pay you a hundred dollars.
Two hundred dollars!
I'll do it...
for five.
What?
I'll pay you $250.
Now, I ain't cheap...
but I can be had.
My minimum price for taking a stranded
woman to a telephone is $400.
- Will you take 375 in traveler's checks?
- American Express?
- Of course.
- You got a deal.
Good.
Señor Zolo.
Assemble your men!
Ow!
You got any valuables
in that suitcase?
No. Yes!
All my clothes and things.
- You got an umbrella?
- No.
- You got a good pair of walking shoes?
- They're all like these.
Uh-huh.
- Okay, let's make some time.
- You b-
Aw, shit!
Oh, goddamn it!
What a ride, huh?
Whoo!
I'm telling you, this is turning out to be
one hell of a morning!
Ah!
You okay?
I said, are you hurt?
What's the matter?
Are you paralyzed from the neck up?
Are you hurt?
- No.
- Good.
- What's your name?
- Uh-Uh-
I'm J-Joan Wilder.
Joan Wilder,
welcome to Colombia!
Hi. Hi.
Oh, hi, Ma.
It's me, Irving.
Ralph, you little twerp,
where are you?
Calm down, Ma.
Who says I never call?
Will you for Christ's sake
tell me the story?
All right, cousin.
As usual, you got us...
in some serious shit here.
First of all, the stupid dame
got on the wrong bus.
Now I'm stuck in some kind
of spico military compound.
They're mobilizing
for Iwo Jima here.
- Do they know who you are?
- Oh-Oh-
What do you think, I'm going up
and introducing myself...
to every cop in the pueblo?
And another
little tidbit, cousin.
- Guess who else is here.
- Zolo.
Oh! Oh, well,
give the man a cigar.
You're goddamned right, Zolo!
He got in my car.
Not only are we kidnappers,
but I'm about to have...
a close encounter
with a cattle prod.
- Has he got his boys with him?
- No, no, no.
He's making do
with the local yo-yos.
Oh, no. Oh!
- Look-
- Goddamn it, Ralph!
- Get that map!
- Don't yell at me, Ira!
Don't yell at me.
Look, you want to kill me?
Take me back to Queens
and kill me.
Don't let me die in a jungle
like a goddamned snake.
Ralph, goddamn it!
I don't care what you gotta do.
Just get me that map!
Little sister
took the wrong road.
And that third party
I told you about...
he's tagging along.
The man who killed my husband?
The butcher
who killed your husband.
A very powerful man with
his own private army to back him up.
And whether he calls himself Dr. Zolo,
Minister of Antiquities...
or Colonel Zolo, Deputy Commander
of the Secret Police...
he's still just a butcher.
Look at those snappers, will ya?
What's the matter?
You sick?
Uh, no.
I lost my button.
- You lost what?
- I lost my button.
My button.
You"re gonna lose
a lot more than that.
- These were Italian.
- Now they're practical.
Is nothing that I own
sacred to you?
Only your $375.
Cops!
What the hell do they want?
I haven't done anything lately.
I'm shooting at a cop.
- Wait a minute. He's after you.
- Wha-
- Who the hell are you??
- Well, I'm-I'm a romance novelist.
You're what?
- What are you doing here?
- I told you.
- My sister's life depends on me.
- Don't give me that shit.
I thought you were donating
a kidney or something.
Christ, here they come.
This may be a good time
to try on those shoes right about now.
- Wait!
- Deal's off, lady.
Wait!
Lady, you are bad news.
What'd you do,
wake up this morning and say...
“Today I'm gonna ruin
a man's life”?
- Do you know where you're going?
- Looks like some kind of trail.
This is a trail?
Lady, you are a jinx!
Well, what about the bridge?
That ain't a bridge.
Goddamn pre-Colombian art.
You can't get across that.
Aw, shit.
All right, all right.
We're gonna hold 'em off right from here.
You just stay right behind me.
Goddamn it! I knew I should've
listened to my mother.
I could've been
a cosmetic surgeon.
Five hundred thou a year,
up to my neck in tits and ass.
Lady, I hope
you're taking notes...
'cause you got a real live
death scene going on right here.
Romantic novelist, my ass.
Holy shit!
Joan!
What the hell are you doing?
Drinking? I could've been killed,
and you're drinking!
Wait!
- ¡Vamos!
Are we stopping?
Be my guest.
You okay?
Come on.
- Is anybody else in there?
- No.
No, it's a cargo plane.
What is all this?
All this? About five to life
in the States...
a couple of centuries down here.
Oh, marijuana.
Oh, you smoke it.
- I went to college.
- Yeah, sure.
- All right! Okay.
- Oh!
Oh, God, do I love
those flyboys.
What?
This is Elaine's favorite drink.
You gonna tell me about
that sister of yours?
I already did.
Her husband died, and-
and I've come down here
to comfort her.
- Uh-huh.
- It's the truth.
Right. Yeah,
it's the truth.
All right.
I'm gonna make a fire.
You got any dry matches in here?
Well, lookie here.
Uh-Oh, no, don't!
I think you and I
oughta have a talk.
All right.
Yeah, that's what I call
a campfire.
Whoo!
So they're ransoming
your sister for this El Corazon.
That's Spanish for “The Heart.”
This map here
leads to The Heart.
But the heart of what?
I don't care.
You see here where it says
this El Corazon is hidden...
in Cordoba province?
Mm-hmm.
So we're sitting
right in the middle of it.
All I care about is my sister,
and that map is her life.
Like hell it is. Whatever's at the end
of this map is your sister's life.
Now, we get our hands
on this El Corazon...
then you got something
to bargain with.
- I knew it would happen.
- You knew what would happen?
All you care about
is yourself, isn't it?
I knew that from the first moment
I laid eyes on you.
( Oh, is that the first moment
when I saved your ass? I Chuckles )
There. You see?
There you go.
You have no finesse, no style.
A real man doesn't have to-
to draw attention to his actions.
You're-You're just-
You're a mondo-dizmo.
I'm-What am I? I'm what?
You're a man who takes money
from stranded women.
A real man, he's honest...
and forthright and trustworthy.
Would you please do me the courtesy of
looking at me when I'm speaking to you?
I mean, this is exactly
what I'm talking about.
I mean, if you had any
kind of manners-If you-
Goddamn bushmaster.
Is it, uh, poisonous?
Yeah, but very tasty.
Uh-oh.
Uniforme.
See, you gotta figure
sulphur-crested cockatoos...
they go for about 800 a shot.
Then you got gentle red-tails.
They're-They're close
to 2,000 each.
Shit, I figure I lost close to
15,000 bucks in that bus crash.
- Wow!
- Mm-hmm.
You wanna know something crazy?
- What?
- I don't even know your name.
Well, you never asked me.
Excuse me.
I'd really like to know-
Colton.
Jack T. Colton.
- What does the “T” stand for?
- Aw, goddamn it, man!
The Doobie Brothers broke up.
Shit!
- When did that happen?
- How long have you been down here?
Aw, man!
- Forever. I don't know.
- Were you always into birds?
Mm-mm. No, no.
I, uh-
No, I was, uh-
I was into shortcuts.
Birds just seemed to be
a fast way to get what I wanted.
And a hell of a lot healthier
than dealing in this crap.
What is it you want?
I think I'm gonna throw
another key on the fire.
No, please.
I'm getting dizzy.
What do you want, seriously?
I'd really like to know.
I came down here on a coffee boat
about a year and a half ago, right?
Christ, what a job that was.
But I couldn't get over
that ocean though, you know?
Yeah, I love the ocean.
You know, you just
gotta get out there all by yourself.
Nobody else around.
It's beautiful.
So that's what I want.
Try to get enough money together,
buy a boat...
sail around the world.
So you're just gonna
sail away all by yourself?
Yeah.
Sounds lonely, Jack T. Colton.
Well, what does
the “T” stand for?
Trustworthy.
Mmm.
Aw, man, I tell ya,
one hell of a morning.
It's turned into
a bitch of a day.
“Tenedor dell Diablo.”
The Devil's Fork.
Zolo.
- Friendly, aren't they?
- Drug runners.
Just try to look mean.
Buenos Dias.
- Oh, shit.
- What's the matter?
Nothing.
Hey, hombre.
Hey, hombre!
- Okay, here we go.
- What?
I just knew I should've
listened to my mother.
Hey, hombre.
You ready?
Uh, excuse me.
Gentlemen,
we are in need of a car.
Can any of you lovely gentlemen
tell me where-
Only one car in village.
Juan, the bell maker.
The bell maker.
Thank you.
Bell maker, my ass.
That fuselage we slept in is probably
one of old Juan's lost shipments.
- You mean he's a drug de-
- Shh!
- Just don't say the word out loud, okay?
- Dope?
Come on.
Let's go.
All right.
Now, you-you hold back.
This one I'll handle.
What do you want, gringo?
Oh, you speak English.
Oh, that's-that's great.
We understand that
you have a car.
We would like
to rent it or buy it.
We have to get to a town.
What do you call this
I'm livin' in, a pigsty?
Uh, no. No, no.
This is lovely. It's-
- Hit the road.
- No, amigo, you don't understand-
- Senor, I'd-
Vaya con Dios, gringo.
It's cool.
It's... no problem.
Vaya con Dios.
Oh.
Okay, Joan Wilder,
write us out of this one.
Joan Wilder?
The Joan Wilder?
You are Joan Wilder,
the novelist?
Yes, I am.
I read your books.
I read all your books.
Come In.
The one who writes
the books I read to you on Saturdays.
Juanita.
Es Juanita.
- Come in.
- Adios, Amiga.
I can't believe you're here.
Joan Wilder.
Oh.
I've been reading your books
all these years.
I'm so honored to have you here.
I can't believe it.
Welcome to my humble house.
Joan Wilder!
Oh, I-I'm sorry.
I haven't introduced myself.
I'm Juan.
I live here.
¿Qué Paso?
The greatest novelist.
Get the door, please.
Buenos Dias.
¿Gringos?
¿Americanos?
- ;Gringos?
- No.
- ¿Americanos?
Come In.
Make yourself at home.
- Ever read The Return of Angelina?
- No.
That woman makes me hungry.
How about Love's Wicked Kiss?
No, I haven't read
that one either.
Read it. Take it.
I have many copies.
I have here The Ravagers, and I am
waiting for Angelina's Savage Secret.
I am so glad you're
here in Colombia.
I want to show you all
around my beautiful village.
We have colorful tile roofs, typical
cobblestone streets and very rich fields.
I was born here
and so was my whole family.
What I would really
like would be a phone.
No, no, no. No phones.
I hate phones.
I don't have a phone.
But have a drink.
Let's hang out. Look.
Like it? I can be in one of your books.
Oh, your drink.
I got Southern Comfort.
Or Michelob, Kirin,
Becks, Dos Equis...
Perrier, Anchor Steam,
Dr. Brown-
- How about a Xerox machine?
- Yes, but she is broken.
Where is the nearest phone?
- Many miles from here.
- Can we get there in your car?
- Who told you I had a car?
- The men in the village.
They told you I had a car?
They're such comedians.
They meant my little mule Pepe.
Not bad for a little mule, eh?
Now Pepe's warming up.
- What are we stopping for?
- I can't hurt my favorite pig.
Look out!
Watch it!
I - Oh!
See over there by the fence?
That's where my mother was born.
And see that tree? The third tree up
the ridge? My brother planted that tree.
Okay, Pepe, let's lose 'em.
Whoa!
- This guy's crazier than I am.
- Gracias. Yeah!
What the hell you doin'?
That field was cover.
I wanted to show you
this other field.
Oh, shit!
This guy who's following you,
he's very persistent.
No problem.
My Little Mule is fireproof.
- See that river?
- What, the one without the bridge?
This river is the main water
supply for many villages.
What do you mean, “the
one without the bridge”?
It feed's right into the Amazon.
The one without the bridge.
Where the hell are you going?
Lupe's Escape.
I've used it many times in the past.
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
You're okay now.
You need Little Mule
to use Lupe's Escape.
You know, that river is impossible to cross
for 200 miles in either direction.
In fact over that mountain
the river becomes wild.
Muy peligroso.
Waterfalls, rapids.
Angelina country.
Right, Joan?
- Whatever happened to Lupe?
- Oh, ay, ay, ay.
- Terrible disappointment to family.
- / can imagine.
He entered the priesthood,
so I took over the business.
It's for the best.
I'm not so reckless.
He might have ended up hanging from
El Tenedor Del Diablo there.
- It used to happen to barndidos.
- “El Tenedor dell Diablo”?
Okay. Hey, let's hit it. We're on a roll.
I'm sorry I cannot take you
all the way to Cartagena.
Beyond this town
I am a wanted man.
But in the morning
there is always a bus.
It will take you.
Of all the things
you can say to me right now...
“I've lost her”, Ralph, is gonna get
the most teeth broken in your mouth.
Look, bullet head, if they're hiking
through the jungle...
there's nothin'
I can do about it.
I have a car.
I am not Tarzan.
I have been through every one-horse
shithole for a 200-mile radius.
You should have seen the river
I had to traverse this morning.
So don't give me any of
your crap, you gutless wonder.
You have been an embarrassment to me and
the whole family ever since you were born.
And one more thing, Ira-
- Joan.
- Yeah?
You are the luckiest son of a bitch that
walked the face of the earth. She's here.
- She's there?
- She's right here.
She's coming right
toward the phone booth.
She's with some guy.
How do I know?
She likes guys.
So do you, maricón.
Yeah, all the rooms have baths.
Oh, that's-that's great.
You speak English too.
That's great.
Listen, you wouldn't have a Xerox machine
around here, would you?
Yeah.
We have one in the back.
I mean, it's big enough
to take, like, uh, map size?
Yeah. Complete.
Yes, I understand.
I'll do that.
Well, I talked to Blaine.
She's all right.
They're gonna wait for me
to take the bus in the morning.
That's great. Then
slide, man. You're covered.
I don't know.
- He sounded so smug.
- Who?
- That bastard that's got Elaine.
- Sure he is.
You're bringing what he wants.
You're bringing him the map.
Yeah.
Well, I guess this is it.
Uh, yeah, I guess so.
Oh.
375.
That was the contract, right?
Yeah. That was it.
The least I can do
is buy you some dinner.
Looks like it's gonna
be a hell of a party.
I'd like that.
Tell you what.
Uh, I got a room in the hotel.
Why don't you go get cleaned up?
I'll buy us some new rags.
- Number seven.
- Seven? That's my lucky number.
Mine too.
It's just beautiful.
Thank you, jack.
I think your writing's hot. It's great.
I mean it. I'm tellin' you.
I'm impressed. I am.
You've never even read the book.
I know.
I suppose...
it's my way of living
in another age.
If you did that,
I never would have met you.
I got you something.
El Corazon?
- Let's dance.
- Oh, no. I can't.
- Come on. I'll show you.
- I-No.
- No.
- Try. Trust me.
Jo'
I- I lost my langostino.
No, no, no, no! Wait!
No, no! Wait!
Calm down, lady!
Jo'
Señora.
Someday, if I had the money,
I'd take you...
I'd sail away.
Just the two of us.
Around the world and back again.
I promise you.
I promise you we'd do that.
Why haven't you taken
the map away from me?
What are you talking about?
I saw that tree today,
the Devil's Fork that's on the map.
You know how close we are?
Well, sure I do, but what has that
got to do with it?
I was thinking about something you said,
about having more to bargain with.
Yeah. Yeah, the best way to help your
sister is to get that treasure.
Then you could waltz into Cartagena.
You're holding all the cards.
I'd love to see you
on that boat.
But, Jack, if we have to give it
up to save Elaine-
Then we give it
up. I mean, it's your
sister. Hell, yeah. Of
course we give it up.
But that's the point.
At least we've got the leverage to do it.
Okay.
Let's go for it.
Shh!
Shh, shh, shh, shh!
He just won't quit.
- What are you doing?
- I'm hot-wiring the car.
Try the key.
- There it is. That's the shrine.
- Yep.
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
Well, this-this can't be all.
There's gotta be
another clue here.
Well, landmarks change,
things grow.
All that stuff, you know?
Oh. Hey, you hear that?
Waterfall.
Look, Jack.
All right, Joan!
Whoo!
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Whoa!
This has got to be it.
Hey, what-
what does
“Leche de la Madre” mean?
Leche de la Madre?
Yeah. It's on the map.
It means “mother's milk”.
- Mother's milk?
- Yeah.
I'll be goddamned,
Mama, I'm home.
- I can't believe I'm doing this.
- What?
Digging for treasure...
with you.
Jack?
Yeah?
You're the best time
I've ever had.
I never been anybody's
best time before.
It's a priceless statue.
Somebody out there's got
a really sick sense of humor.
Wait a minute.
My first book,
Treasures of Lust..
I hid the treasure
inside the statue.
Oh.
Jesus Christ,
we're in a lot of trouble.
Understatement of the year,
asshole.
Is there anybody
who isn't following you?
Put the goods in the bag.
Come on.
Now move it,
before Batman comes home.
It's time I had a chauffeur,
Miss Wilder.
Back off me, creep!
Just back off!
Oh. Oh, I'm the creep, huh?
Well, at least I'm honest.
I'm stealin' this stone. I'm not tryin'
to romance it out from under her.
Wait a minute now.
Going for the stone was my idea.
Aw, that's what all the good
con artists want you to think.
He made you think you needed it,
you sap. Get in and drive.
Come on. Move it.
Move it.
Move it!
See how you like being stuck in-
Holy shit!
Oh! Get in!
- Which way do we go?
- Follow that stone!
Mounties!
Hit it!
- Where the hell you goin'?
- Where am I goin'?
How about Lupe's Escape?
Whoa!
Where you goin'? Quit steering.
You're not going anywhere.
Oh, no!
- What are we gonna do now?
- Jump!
Hey!
Joan Wilder, hey!
What a comeback!
Yeah.
Man, I thought you drowned.
I did.
- You okay?
- Oh, sure.
I'm great.
I'm fine.
Only you're on that side.
There's no way
across this sucker.
You did this on purpose!
What the hell are you talkin' about?
We just went over a waterfall!
Admit it!
You planned this all along.
I knew I couldn't depend on you.
I knew it!
What's the name of
that hotel in Cartagena?
Hotel Cartagena.
What do you care?
All right. Now, you just head towards
the sunset, and you'll make it.
- And I'll be there.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
With El Corazon in your pocket.
What about my sister?
Well, they don't have to know about this.
You got the map.
- Well, you've got the stone.
- Yeah.
- I'll meet you there! Trust me!
- What?
So you made it finally.
Got the map?
Yes. I brought it. I
want to talk to Elaine.
No, you can't talk to her
till I get it.
All right.
Now look out your window.
- See the fort across the bay? The tower?
- Yes.
You take a water taxi
right outside your hotel.
You meet me there
in two hours, all by yourself.
- Hello?
- Has Jack Colton checked in?
In the last two minutes, no.
Over here.
Stop right there.
Let me see the map.
- Where are you?
- Let me see the map.
- Let me see Elaine.
- Joanie?
Drop the map and back off.
If this isn't genuine-
If you've pulled a fast one-
Joan Wilder...
you and your sister...
can go!
Hey.
It's okay.
It's all right.
I missed you at the hotel.
We all did.
You brainless broad.
You let him follow you here.
This map is nothing.
They already have the stone.
I had it in my hands, Ira.
These hands that are gonna
break every bone in your body.
Later.
- Where is it?
- I don't know.
- Where is the stone?
- I don't-
We dug. We didn't find anything.
Crocodiles shed tears
when they eat their prey.
You have heard of these tears,
I am sure.
But have you seen them?
Stop it!
Look at those snappers.
You can fore-go this agony.
Simply tell me, where is El Corazon?
Where is The Heart?
- Where is the stone?
- All right! Just let her go, will you?
She doesn't know where it is.
I've got it.
Where is it?
- It's in a safe place.
- Where is it?
Where is it?
Choke on it.
Thank you.
Get down!
All right, honey, come on.
Hurry! Hurry!
Guys! Muchachos!
Bring the boat around!
Hold them down!
Let me get to the boat!
- Just a little more. Come on.
- Where are we going?
¡Muchachos!
¡Ándale!
Vámonos!
Ira!
- Come back here, Ira!
- Jump, Ralph! Jump!
I can't swim.
You know that, Ira.
I'll come back for you.
- You promise?
- I'll send the boat back for you, Ralph!
- When?
- Soon!
- How soon?
- Very soon!
No. No.
No!
Where do you think
you're going, old pal?
Come on.
Cough it up.
Wait!
Joanie?
How will you die, Joan Wilder?
Slow like a snail?
Or fast like a shooting star?
'Jack!
»
Jack!
Come on, you bastard. Give me a break.
Damn it!
Jack.
It's okay.
Come on back, Ira!
Ira!
You're my cousin, Ira!
Don't you remember?
I'll be back!
Your mother, my mother!
That way! That way!
He's gettin' away!
- He's got it all! Go that way!
- Let's get outta here!
- Joanie?
- Yeah?
Okay. All right.
Here's what we gotta do.
Get to the American consulate.
Just-Just tell 'em everything.
Where are you going?
They might even believe
you. But just one thing:
Don't mention my name.
Cartagena cops and I go way back.
- Elaine, it's been a pleasure.
- You're leaving? You're leaving me?
You're gonna be all right,
Joan Wilder.
Yeah.
You always were.
Jack Colton!
Damn.
Well, that is far and away
your best book.
I can't believe how fast
you cranked this out.
So you really like it?
Like it? Look at me.
Look at me. I'm a mess.
It made me cry. Don't tell anybody,
or I'll cut your heart out.
I love the end where he dives off
the high wall and swims away.
And then he meets her at the airport.
They sail off around the world together.
God, I can't believe
how this got to me.
Well, I was, uh, inspired.
Joanie, you are now
a world-class hopeless romantic.
No. Hopeful.
Hopeful romantic.
- Hey, lady.
- Hey, pretty lady.
- No, thanks. Nope.
- Come on. Name brand. Name brand.
Never wear 'em.
This will look great
with what you're
wearin' right now.
Five dollars, it's yours.
Hey!
I like your boots.
Yep. That poor old yellow-tailed guy
developed a fatal case of indigestion.
Died right in my arms.
I can't blame him.
If I were to die...
there's nowhere else
on earth I'd rather be.
I couldn't stop
thinking about you.
I even read one of your books.
- Then you know how they all end.
- Yeah.
- Hi.