I received
I have started the main engines.
I Four, three , two, one ...
Subtitles : Subtitles Avocatul31 - Noi Team
Sync by noi.ro
You're an asshole , Thom .
Look, Celia must follow our passions .
You have your own robot , and I
I just want to be great in space.
Why not admit it simply
you're horrified by my hand robot?
There are terrified of ... It is ...
All right , all right !
I am appalled !
I 'm allergic nightmares
by these giant robotic tongs
of death ...
Regardless, Thom . I finished .
I 40 years later
Memory was synchronized robots
And insured!
That is scary .
It should not be down there?
I've heard you talk last night .
19th
00:02:16,000 - > 00:02:18,000
You know , it's not my fault.
Are you ready ?
Of course you're ready ,
You're a rock star .
How is the situation , Barley ?
We should have ten minutes ...
Well, this is perfect.
We start in a minute! Start
All systems ! Yes , you start!
26th
Come on ! Not move up! Come , come !
27th
Come on . Come on , start !
28th
That is beautiful .
29th
Do you have nothing to worry about .
Thom .
Thom , forget it.
Now ...
You love her .
It is your passion!
Be gentle with her.
Be honest ! Be gentle ...
Remind them what love is.
w.w.w.s.u.b.t.i.t.r.a.r.i - n.o.i.r.o
And I. .. I action
Memory Initialization in progress !
I'm sorry !
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Look, Celia .
You have to follow our passions .
You have your own robot ...
and I just want to be great in space.
Well , come . Remained two minutes !
I two minutes.
Vivacissimo !
Why will not you admit it you're
Terrified of my hand robot?
I Celia , I love your hand robot.
Listen, Celia , I was young ...
And I was a moron .
But that is no reason
to destroy the world .
Why do this ?
I already tried that!
Cancel !
Cut !
I Error
No!
You have broken my heart .
I know .
You forgot the earth.
- It should be simply to crush you .
- I know .
I ...
I'm sorry.
A good improvisation .
It is not my fault!
This time ...
I Quiet on the set !
I do not have time ! Do not have time
Come on !
The memory is loaded 90%.
Captain ! Had to cancel !
The world has changed , Celia ...
Maybe we can do and we this.
Memory has been fully charged !
You know ...
For this you must learn a lesson .
It could have been worse .
Subtitles : Subtitles Avocatul31 - Noi Team
Sync by noi.ro