(DRUM ROLL)
(FANFARE)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
MAN: Anyone else would die here
of thirst in a few days,
because in this arid desert
that looks like a paradise,
there is no surface water.
But the slender and
graceful little Bushmen
of the deep Kalahari
live here contentedly,
and in complete harmony
with their environment.
They have lived here undisturbed
for 20,000 years
because they are the only people
in the world
who know how to live
without surface water.
When ivory poachers in
high tech vehicles
intrude into this vast thirst-land
to hunt elephant,
they have to drag giant reservoirs
of water with them.
And when the water runs low,
they have to hightail it
out of the Kalahari again.
So the Bushmen work and play
in peaceful isolation
quite unaware of the crowded
and hectic world
outside their domain,
and even of the wars
that are being fought
on the very fringes
of the Kalahari.
Sometimes Xixo tells about the time
when he went to look
for the end of the Earth,
and about the strange,
heavy people he met on his journey,
but he finds it difficult
to describe the beings
who live outside the Kalahari.
And he always ends up by saying
that the heavy people are persons
who seem to know some magic
that can make things move
and even fly,
but that they're not very bright,
because they can't survive
without their magic contrivances.
In the mornings, they
like to read the news.
They can read that the hyena
has a new girlfriend,
that the cheetah has lost
one of her babies,
and the oryx is starting to migrate
to the west.
The older children
teach the younger ones
how to read all the gossip
about their neighbors,
the animals,
because everything that
happens in the Kalahari
gets printed out in the sand.
MAN:
So it's all printed out here.
This is where they started
infringing on your client's patent.
Give it to me there.
Now, that I can present in court.
Go back to frame A.
And give me sales.
Oh, go away, Geoff.
- Cathy, will you take this?
- CATHY: Okay.
Take him off.
Now, cost per unit.
And a printout on that.
Mr. Geoffrey says he has to go
to Hong Kong about the takeover.
Okay. Tell him to
have a good flight.
So, uh, he won't make
the ECACL conference.
He can't do that to me.
He said he'd like you
to read the paper.
Says, uh, you did most of
the research,
so you deserve the honor.
I deserve to be left alone
so I can take this case
to court on Wednesday.
Oh, he says there you'll
be back before Wednesday.
Oh, boy.
That morning, Xabe
came out of the forest
with the news that
some of the animals
had started moving towards
the marula groves in the north.
He ran up to his father
and shouted,
"The marulas are ripe.
Let's go and collect some."
But then Xisa and
little Xiri ran up and said,
"Can we come too?"
Xixo said, "Let's see if
you're big enough yet.
"If you're taller than my bow,
"the hyena will be afraid of you
"and he'll keep his distance.
"But if you're shorter,
he'll take you."
But Xiri said,
"Please let me come too."
And Xisa said,
"I promise I'll
always stay close to him."
Where are they having
the conference this year?
In Okakarara.
- Where's that, Nebraska?
- No, Africa.
Oh, boy.
They gathered a lot of marulas,
and on the way home
they came across
the spoor of a wounded elephant.
Xixo said,
"This elephant is very weak.
It's going to die."
He said to Xisa,
"You and Xiri can go on home.
"Tell your mother we will come
when we've found
the sick elephant."
There was a very strange
and very beautiful pattern
on the ground.
Xisa couldn't read it.
She'd never seen anything
like it in her life.
There was another one
just as beautiful as
the first one.
She wondered how anything
could make
such a long, unbroken track.
She followed the track
and saw a very
strange-looking thing.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
She said, "You see, this
thing went round and round,
and that's how it made
such a long pattern
without footprints."
Xiri saw
a beautiful dewdrop grow,
and when it dropped,
another one began
to grow in its place.
They knew that the gods
always put dewdrops on
plants in the night.
But here they could see
a dewdrop form
in broad daylight.
Xisa said,
"I think this thing
is making the water."
Xiri had never seen so
much water in his life.
He didn't know there was
so much water
in the whole world.
(ENGINE STARTS)
They found the elephant,
and they saw the tiny wound
that had made it die.
The tracks told Xixo that the
heavy people had been there,
and he wondered why they
had taken the useless tusks,
and had left all the
valuable meat to rot.
He said, "The heavy
people do strange things."
Bo said, "I'll call Xabo's
family to help us eat the meat.
If I run all day and night,
I can find them by tomorrow."
And Xixo said,
"We'll go and call our family."
There were many tusks.
It takes the gods
more than a man's lifetime
to make a full-grown elephant,
and it horrified them to see
that so many had died.
Xixo and Xabe found the place
where Xisa and Xiri's tracks
suddenly stopped.
Xixo said, "Look,
Xisa climbed onto the thing,
and then Xiri went up too,
and it took them away."
He said, "Tell our family they must
go to the dead elephant,
"and start eating it.
I'll fetch Xisa and Xiri."
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I'm sorry you had to come
on such short notice,
but we're very honored
to have you.
Thank you.
I would have liked
going on the safari tour,
but I have to prepare
my presentation.
You sure you'll be
all right here?
I'll be fine, thank you.
Good, then I'll leave you to it.
All right. Bye.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
You know where Stephen's
working at the moment?
Yeah, I think I've got
a rough idea.
Well, you may have to
search around for him a bit.
Right.
- And Jack?
- Yeah?
Tell Stephen we'll send
the rest of the stuff
out to him later.
Right.
What's a nice girl like you
doing in a place like this?
- Oh, boy.
- You don't buy it.
-Mm-mm
-Okay, I'll try again.
Hi. How would you like to
come fly with me?
I have to work on this. That's
why I turned down the safari trip.
Trip's three hours.
I could show you lots of Africa
in half an hour.
What do you say?
I have to present this
at 3:30, you know.
Oops.
- Only half an hour?
- Yes, doctor.
So, uh, what are you,
a doctor of medicine?
No, corporate law.
What a tiny plane.
We have a smaller one
but we can't find it.
- Can it fly?
- In you go.
(ENGINE BUZZING)
- ANNE: What are those?
- JACK: Buffalo.
Look, no hands.
Flies by itself.
Safest plane in the world.
- Coffee.
- Morning, boss.
You only done 80 miles.
Yeah, I slept a little bit.
You stopped.
I was bushed.
So I pulled up and...
You slept more than four hours.
I was real pooped.
I told you we're running late.
I was really pooped, boss.
Move over.
It's okay, boss.
I'm fresh now.
Jeez, boss.
Lazy bastard.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Get back to sleep.
I'm wide awake now.
- Sleep.
- Yes, boss.
- I'll be right back.
- Mm-hm.
- Hi, Stephen.
- Hi. Thanks.
You're cutting it fine,
you know.
There's a hell of a cumulus
building up.
One of those thermals
grabs hold of you,
it's gonna whip you
right over the escarpment,
to 20,000, 30,000 feet.
See you later.
MAN (ON RADIO): Stephen,
is Jack there yet? Over.
Hi, Bob. Yes,
he's here. Over.
Can you fly back in with him?
We found a baby giraffe
that looks very sick.
We need your advice.
Over.
Okay. Out.
You know you're not supposed to
cart your floozies
around in that.
No, she's not a floozy.
- Hi.
- Morning.
Do you do some kind
of work around here?
(ENGINE BUZZING)
BOB: Hello, Stephen.
Come in. Over.
Stephen,
are you there? Over.
Hello, Stephen,
come in. Over.
Hi, Bob.
This is Jack. Over.
Jack, don't take off yet.
There's a freak storm
moving in very fast
across the escarpment.
Over.
Uh, Bob, they've just
taken off. Over.
They? Is there someone else
with him? Over.
Yes. Over.
Who? Over.
Uh, there was this
young lady. Over.
Was she with you? Over.
Uh, sort of. Over.
Boy, you're in trouble.
Over.
Xixo's old friend Waka
was standing there
looking at the tracks
the heavy people had made.
Xixo greeted him
and told him that
his children were in the
thing that had made the tracks.
Waka greeted him back and said,
"I'll come with you
to find your children."
But Xixo said, "There's a
dead elephant back there.
"Go there with your family
so they can help my family
eat it."
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(YELPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
They stopped.
I think there's some whiskey
under your seat.
No, thanks.
I'm okay.
Give it to me.
You're gonna start drinking?
Give me.
Can this thing fly on Scotch?
(ENGINE STARTS)
George.
Boss?
Take over.
Xisa said,
"When this thing gets tired
it will stop to rest.
Then we can follow
the tracks back home."
(WIND BLOWING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
Running out of Scotch.
This any good?
No.
(WIND BLOWING)
We're flying backwards.
I have to read
my paper at 3:30.
How do I get back?
We have to find a road
so I can hitch a ride.
So which way to
the nearest road?
This is baobab country.
Oh, it can speak.
We're at least
300 miles from base.
Oh, boy.
Maybe more.
- (SCREECHING)
- (GASPING)
- I'm sorry.
- Any time.
I have to get to a telephone.
I don't even know what
country we're in.
That was one hell of a storm.
Hey!
(MUTTERING)
- What?
- They're not scared of me.
- So?
- They don't know about people.
We're in the deep Kalahari.
Will they find us here?
Eventually.
Well, how long is eventually?
Maybe a day, maybe a week.
A week?
I have to be back in
New York on Wednesday.
You're from New York?
You mean I have to
survive here for a week?
Anyone who can survive in
New York can survive here.
We'll starve to death.
There's enough food around here.
Our problem will be water.
All we have is that
six-pack up there.
They were getting quite thirsty,
but they knew where
there was plenty of water.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
She said, "No, I'm too
heavy for you to pull me up.
"You come down here
so you can push me up.
Then I can pull you up."
Xiri had never been
in water in his life,
but soon got used to the idea,
and quite enjoyed it.
Is that water?
- Petrol. Gas.
- So?
If I can get this down, we can fly out.
Today?
I have to take it apart,
bring it down,
assemble it again.
Eventually.
Maybe by tomorrow, the next day.
- (DISTANT ROARING)
- Was that a lion?
Yeah, I can hear them.
Let down the rope. I want to get up.
- They won't bother us.
- You're okay.
They're bothering
the hell out of me down here.
Will you let down that rope?
They're not coming this way.
ANN:
What about eventually?
You don't bother them,
they won't bother you.
And if they're hungry?
They're far from here.
(GRUNTING, SQUEALING)
(GROWLING, HISSING)
It's swarming with
wild animals down here.
If you don't bother them,
they won't bother you.
I'm not bothering them.
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(HYENA LAUGHING)
This one is drooling at me.
It's a hyena.
They're always drooling.
- So?
- Ignore him.
- Don't smile at him.
- Why not?
He sees your teeth,
he might think you're threatening him.
Let me get up there.
- (GASPS)
- (ANIMAL YELPING)
You're enjoying this.
Yeah. Why don't you relax
and enjoy it too?
What's to enjoy?
Wild animals all over the place,
no food, no water.
No room service.
Yeah, no plumbing.
What I need is plumbing.
Now.
Go behind that thicket.
Alone? I mean, the lions are that way.
They're very far.
If you don't bother them...
They won't bother me.
I know, I know.
How do I get down?
How'd you get up there?
The lion was roaring.
Wasn't a lion.
It was a hyena sounding off.
Right.
Now, just a minute.
Turn your back.
- Pull me up, pull me up.
- I can't. Friction.
Then let me down.
- Stop.
- What do you want me to do?
- Don't look at me.
- I'm not looking at you.
- What do you want me to do?
- Let me down, let me down.
(LAUGHING)
What's so funny?
(GASPS)
Okay, I won't bother you, see?
So don't you bother me.
(SNORTING, GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
- Watch it!
- Go away!
Run, run, run, run, run, run.
Get up a tree!
You okay?
You said if I didn't bother them...
I see there's a baby rhino
back there.
Maybe the mother thought
you were molesting it.
I only talked to it.
I didn't even smile at it.
It's okay.
They're going away now.
I'm not coming down
before you can
fly me out of here.
There's no plumbing up there.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- You thirsty?
- Yes.
Right, you can have half a beer.
Great.
Don't open it yet.
Sorry.
Oh, my goodness.
What did I do wrong?
Well, it's warm.
Drink it now.
(LAUGHING)
Right.
It's getting late.
We have to find food
before it gets dark.
I saw an ostrich nest.
ANN: Do they bite?
No, they kick.
But they aren't very bright.
If you lie down flat,
he can't see you.
That's the male.
He has to guard the eggs.
But if you can distract him...
How do I distract
a male ostrich?
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Lie down flat!
(GROWLING)
(SCREECHING)
For a moment,
Xixo thought he saw
his children's footprints,
but it was only a baboon
that had walked past.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GUNSHOT)
So, what went wrong?
Nothing. We got the egg.
You mean that was
standard procedure?
- Got a match?
- (GASPS)
The thing came back.
I'm sorry.
You got a match?
I got a lighter.
BEN: Big Ben calling Ramjee.
Big Ben calling Ramjee.
Do you read me?
(STATIC)
Ramjee, come in.
Big Ben calling.
Come in, Ramjee.
Still out of range.
Maybe they're not there yet.
He said he'd meet us
on the ninth.
That's yesterday.
Sorry, boss.
(RADIO TUNING)
MAN (ON RADIO): ...It is
expected that at least 10,000 people
will attend the opening.
Although nine helicopters
and four spotter planes
are taking part in the search,
no sign of Dr. Marshall and
Dr. Taylor has been found.
- Was that us?
- I suppose so.
- Doctor of what?
- Zoology.
- You?
- Law.
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- We have to watch that guy.
- The hyena?
Yes, he's a hell of a coward.
As long as you're
taller than he is,
he'll keep his distance.
But if you lie down,
he'll sneak up
and take a chunk out of
your face and leg.
You can take first watch.
Call me when the moon
gets to there,
and I'll take it to there,
then you take it to first light.
(ANIMAL NOISES)
Coming down.
- I'm ready.
- For what?
(GASPS)
You only jumped 25 centimeters.
What happened to
standard procedure?
Maybe next time.
Where are we gonna
take off from?
There's a saltpan
about three miles from here.
Well, how many blocks
would that be?
Keep the sun over your
right shoulder.
Stay clear of low branches.
- (GROWLING)
- (YELPS)
- What?
- It's that damn rhino.
It's a male.
It's harmless.
What are you always
climbing up trees for?
I'm not a doctor of zoology.
How am I supposed to know
about males and females?
Damn near wrecked
the nose wheel.
Give me slack.
(GROWLING)
You only jumped 124 centimeters.
These things are dangerous.
It's very small.
(GROWLING)
Yeah, but when it grabs
hold of you it never lets go.
ANN: It's kind of cute.
Hey. No!
(AIR HISSING)
- Now we've got a flat.
- What do I do with this?
I don't know.
Why don't you throw it away?
It'll just come right back.
Can you change the tire?
- Can you undo my boot?
- Why?
It's the one that
stepped on him.
So?
If I give it to him,
he can have his revenge.
There.
(GROWLING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
ANN: Is there enough gas
to take us all the way back?
STEPHEN:
If we get it off the ground.
(ENGINE STARTS)
No, it won't work.
Can't you fix it?
No pump.
You wanna be the wheel.
You're crazy.
You see that stick?
When I shout "now,"
you bring it over this way.
But I can't fly a plane.
It'll lift your side of
the wing,
then you center up.
When I shout again,
you pull it back.
You see? Bring it over,
center up, pull it back.
- Then what?
- Then I'll take over.
But I can't even drive a manual.
Do you wanna kill us both?
You're nuts.
I can't fly a plane.
Do you hear me?
- I can't fly a plane!
- Throttles.
- What?
- Shiny ones,
push them forward.
Here we go.
Come on. Stick it back.
Center up.
I told you I can't fly.
Right, now pull back.
- You said pull back.
- Not way back!
Pull it, pull it, pull it.
Will you make up your mind?
Bring her down, bring her down.
What?
We go that way.
You said
you were gonna take over.
You should have gone
that way. Oh, shit.
Oh, shit.
Trust a woman to do a thing,
and she buggers it up.
(ENGINE BUZZING)
So she buggered it up.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Just look down and read.
It says, "on/off."
Switch it to off, then glide.
(LAUGHING)
Whoa! Whoa!
Oh, please!
I told you I can't fly.
It says,
"ballistic parachute."
Clearly. Distinctly.
Read it.
Press the button.
You'll be okay.
ANN: I told you I can't
even drive a manual.
(SCREAMS)
Oh, it's easy.
Bring it over, center it up,
pull it back,
and get it right, woman!
I showed you so nicely.
I said, "Bring it over."
Not, "Bring it over!"
You'll break your silly neck.
You don't explain properly.
I could have broken my neck.
How the hell am I going to
find you with only one boot?
Better find my boot.
Shoo. Go away.
- (GROWLING)
- (GASPING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
(ENGINE BUZZING)
(GROWLING)
Oh, shit.
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Wait!
Hi. Do you want to
sell me your bike?
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Look. I'll give you money.
I give you money,
you give me the bike.
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
No, I have to go that way.
There's a man there.
I'll pay you,
you take me that way.
Okay.
- Here.
- (SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Please, I insist.
Okay. Pay you when
we get there.
- There?
- (SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(BIKE HORN HONKING)
(CLUCKING)
(GROWLING)
- (SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- (BIKE HORN HONKING)
ANN: Well, why don't we
try something else?
MAN: Okay.
(CLUCKING)
Yeah, sure.
- (SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- All right.
Good thinking.
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SIGHS)
Are you gonna
hang in there forever?
There. Lunch.
Go on, try it.
(GROWLING)
Okay, try that.
(SCREECHING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(ANNE SCREAMS)
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING)
(PANTING)
(CLUCKING)
Look, I'm really sorry.
Please, take this.
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
No, come on.
Bye.
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Well, thanks. Bye.
Gotta find somebody.
(PANTING)
You said you were tired.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(ENGINE STARTS)
Hey, go home.
Go back to your family.
Go on, get.
Get. Shoo. Go.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(LAUGHING)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(GRUNTS)
(ENGINE GRINDING)
(ENGINE STALLS)
- (SQUAWKING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (SHOUTING)
- (GUNFIRE)
(GUNSHOTS)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
English?
Okay.
Get up.
- Move.
- Which way?
To my jeep.
Stop!
Where are you going?
Where is your jeep?
We go to your jeep.
Stop.
(ENGINE STARTS)
- March.
- Which way?
You know why a compass
has a mirror on the back?
- Why?
- So you can see who's lost.
Okay. We go northwest.
That way. March.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(WIND BLOWING)
How far did you fly,
for Pete's sake?
How the hell am I
gonna find you?
Damn!
Hey.
Hey, you, get away.
Leave it alone.
Get out of here!
Give me back my can!
Scumbag!
You mugger!
Thank you.
You keep away.
Stay there.
See these?
You dare...
Don't even think about it.
You'll be sorry.
Go away.
Okay. You can have
this one and no more.
Leave the can.
Do you hear me?
Leave my can alone and go away!
(GROWLING)
No, don't bring a friend.
I'm not gonna water you
and your friends
and your relatives,
and I'm not... Ah!
(GRUNTING)
(YAWNING)
Excerpts from
the Geneva Convention.
Forget it.
It says here about how
a prisoner of war
ought to be treated.
"No prisoner of war shall be
subjected to inhumane treatment.
No outrage
shall be committed."
Okay. Stop.
You can rest for three minutes.
What's your bloody hurry?
None of your business.
Three minutes.
(ENGINE STARTS)
I'm pooped, man.
Hey! Don't do that.
Come back.
I'm going to report you to
the Geneva Convention!
Come back.
You're my prisoner.
Come back!
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Come out of there
and be my prisoner!
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (SCREAMING)
You mustn't do that!
March.
So if you're so smart,
how come you don't even know
what country you're in?
So which way did they go?
I'll just have to wait
till they come back.
(MAN TALKING ON RADIO)
Xixo saw a heavy person
dressed in funny clothes
sitting next to the track
talking to herself.
She looked like a woman,
but had a man's voice.
(XIXO SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Hey.
Oh, it's your way of greeting.
We do it this way.
Sorry.
Okay. I'll do it your way.
Hello. I'm very glad
to meet you.
He said, "Where
is your family?"
He looked at her tracks
and said,
"You are alone.
How did you get here?"
He said, "I have to find
my children,
"but there are two heavy people
"playing some kind of game
back there.
"They went that way, and now
I hear them coming this way.
Perhaps they'll let you
play with them."
You want me to go
with you? Uh-huh.
He showed her the tracks
where he met the two heavy men.
He said, "This is where
they turned back.
"See how angry this one was
"because the tired one
grabbed the stick from him.
And then he had to run.
It was very funny."
(LAUGHING)
But of course,
she couldn't understand.
She was also quite illiterate.
She couldn't read the signs
and tracks at all.
We're waiting for a bus?
Well, what do you know.
Go away. Bugger off.
I don't want to see you.
Stop!
Who are you?
Xixo couldn't understand what
these crazy people were playing at.
This thing penetrates.
You wouldn't shoot a lady.
He said, "I have to go
and find my children."
He remembered the men
had bad manners,
so he didn't say
goodbye to them.
Gentlemen, I don't want to be
involved in you wars.
I'm American.
Okay.
Hey, you can't leave me here.
You want me to die?
(WHIMPERS)
Get away from me!
(GRUNTS)
Get away!
Try again, huh?
(GRUNTING)
It's not fair.
You can't both use me.
Let me go! Let me go.
Let me go!
Okay, drop it.
- Drop it.
- Yes, drop it.
Now, drop it.
Yes, drop it, drop it, drop it!
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Can't we negotiate?
I wanna go home.
If I don't get back to Biera
by tomorrow night,
I can't meet my plane
back to Cuba.
And then I gotta spend
another six months
in this goddamn Africa!
And I've got to take you
to my base. Now.
Well, I have to be
in New York on Wednesday.
Sit down. And stay clear of
the goddamn Cuban.
I'll stay clear of
goddamn both of you.
I resent being used as a...
as a hostage object.
Gotta be in New York
on Wednesday.
You should have stayed there.
I didn't ask you to
come out here.
I have to walk my ass off
to find you.
Yike!
(GRUNTS)
Well, good.
(HYENAS LAUGHING)
What's so funny?
Switch it on.
Big Ben calling Ramjee.
- What are you doing?
- What am I doing?
Look at the sun.
You're going the wrong way.
Boss, I'm driving
on the compass.
This thing is made of steel.
You left it there.
Look at the needle.
You buggered the compass,
you stupid bastard.
Jeez, boss, I wasn't thinking.
- I'm real...
- Stop the bloody truck.
MAN: So when did
you put it there?
Well, I drank some coffee
just at sunrise, boss.
Five hours.
Forty degrees off.
Stupid bastard.
Big Ben calling Ramjee.
Do you read me,
for Chrissakes?
Ramjee, come in.
MAN (ON RADIO): Big Ben,
where the hell are you?
Look, I'm sorry.
This idiot has
goddamn bugged the compass.
I've been waiting
three bloody days!
Where the bloody hell are you?
We could have been there,
but we're way off course.
Now we have to backtrack
for at least five hours
to find our bearings.
MAN: We're going back
on our tracks now,
so we'll be out of range again.
I'll contact you when we
come back into range.
(PANTING)
Little Xiri saw hyena tracks.
The spoor was very fresh,
so he knew the hyena
must be close.
And it was downwind, so
it was sure to smell him.
He remembered
his father had said:
"If you're taller than
the hyena,
it'll keep its distance."
(PANTING)
It couldn't understand how
this small creature
had grown tall so suddenly.
- (SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- (WHIMPERING)
Perhaps the hyena hoped that
Xiri would get small again,
so it followed him
at a respectful distance.
Well, we got blown here
in a kind of a plane,
and then I kind of
lost Dr. Marshall.
Get in the jeep. Move.
Wait there.
- Okay, but leave your bag.
- Why?
- You swat people.
- No, I won't. I promise.
Look, I'll take out the rocks.
You got rocks in there?
You drive.
In there.
Start her up.
That way.
Xixo saw another track
made by a heavy person
and the footprints told of
a man who was in a bad way.
He spoke to the track.
He said,
"I can see you need help,
but I must find
my children."
MAN: Turn right.
Stop.
Hey, that's my jeep.
I know, I knew it.
- Go siphon.
- Gas?
But my tank was almost empty.
Oh, dios mio.
Oh, boy.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Hi.
Xixo said, "I don't
know what to do.
"You need someone to
find water for you,
"but I'm worried about
my children.
"I've been running for
two days and a night,
"and I haven't found them.
I think they're
very far."
What have you got?
About two liters.
Fourteen, 15 kilometers.
How much have you got in here?
I suppose about 20 kilometers.
And how far is your base?
Sixty, 65.
Oh, my God.
My base is only 20 kilometers.
Shut up.
Get up.
Watch it!
Stop it!
(GRUNTS)
I said, stop it!
Stop it right now!
Ahh!
(GUNSHOT)
Lady, be careful
with that thing.
- Give it to me.
- I won't.
But I'm the good guy here.
He's a bloody Cuban.
- Give it to me.
- (RAPID GUNFIRE)
Jeez, lady.
Yes, make my day.
Okay, señorita.
My base is only
20 kilometers away.
There gonna be a plane
to Cuba tomorrow.
Give me the gun.
I'll take you there.
This guy doesn't know
where he is.
You couldn't even find
your own jeep.
How are you gonna find
your base?
You can find it.
You're so smart.
- We're going to my base.
- Who says?
- I says!
- Stop it!
You, get behind the wheel.
No.
No, get back.
You gotta stay together.
Take his hand.
I said hold hands!
Okay, get in.
You go around that way.
Okay.
Now, can either of you
fly a plane?
Yeah, I can.
Good. Drive back to
where we started.
- Watch it, boss!
- (HORN HONKS)
Jeez, boss,
we killed a little kid.
Sit down.
- We've got to get out of here.
- But, boss, it was a little kid.
He's okay. He's okay.
- (SNIFFING)
- (WHIMPERS)
(BARKING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GASPING)
- Jeez, Boss, there's another one.
- (HORN HONKS)
Bugger.
(HORN HONKING)
Xiri! Xiri!
Now Xisa didn't know
which way to go.
What if her little brother
had been left back there?
(SOBBING)
ANN: Stop here.
This is where
the Bushman found me.
That means the plane must be...
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
That guy's only bad news.
- Follow him.
- We're low on gas.
- We low on gas.
Follow him.
(PANTING)
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
Hi.
Hold hands.
Get out that side.
Go that way.
Stop.
Goodbye, thank you.
What happened?
It's nothing, just
kind of dehydrated.
Does W stand for water?
I don't have to tell you.
(SNIFFS)
Okay, open your mouth.
Who's the little guy who
gave me that stuff?
I don't know.
He just keeps on
appearing and disappearing.
Who are they?
They're soldiers.
They look very...
affectionate.
No.
- Are they your prisoners?
- Kind of.
We're not.
We're hostages.
She hijacked my jeep
and she kidnapped us.
You did it to me first!
Both of them.
He did it and then he did it.
She hit me first.
You hit him?
Yeah.
She hit me too.
Damn near killed me.
- You hit them?
- Mm-hm.
Took them prisoner with a gun?
Yeah.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
- No, we're still backtracking.
- (GASPS)
- (HORN HONKING)
- (YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Keep going.
- Yes, boss.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
We nearly knocked over
another crazy Bushman.
MAN (ON RADIO): You still
in Bushmen country?
It beats me where
they come from.
You said nobody would see you.
- Bushmen don't count.
- (SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Oh, my God.
Ben, what happened?
BEN: Bloody Bushman was
crawling all over.
What do you mean
crawling all over?
What are you doing?
Hey, you okay?
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
What are you doing?
What were you doing up there?
Did he see the ivory?
I don't know.
He must have.
Then you can't let him go.
That's right.
You a game warden?
Get him in here.
You come with us.
You get in there.
Here.
- Boss?
- Make him get in.
You come with us.
You get in there.
You get in there!
You mustn't do that.
Get in there.
Can't you do anything right?
- Jeez, boss.
- Get me a tie-down.
What are you gonna do, boss?
So what if it's illegal?
They did it to me.
He wants to go that way,
and he wants to go that way.
The one with the gun
gets to say where we go.
And I've got the gun and
I say we go to the plane.
Okay.
In the jeep.
When we get to the plane,
you can have your jeep back.
- And my gun.
- We'll see about that.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
It's his, boss.
ANN: Stop.
Here are those tracks again.
Okay, the plane
must be that way.
How are we gonna take off?
I'm not gonna be the wheel again.
Now we can fix it.
I don't see a pump.
Don't!
You've got to watch them.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
- One of yours?
- No.
Game rangers.
What are we gonna do, boss?
He's got a gun.
Don't let him see the ivory.
Maybe they've got a pump.
Hi. Could you
lend us a pump?
- BEN: What?
- (GRUNTING)
Could we borrow a pump with a...
Oh, no!
What have you done to him?
Ahh!
Drop that!
Throw it away!
George.
Get the gun.
What do we do now, boss?
- Tie them up.
- Boss?
Give me that.
- Get the tie-downs.
- Yes, boss.
- What's this all about?
- I don't like game rangers.
- I'm not a game ranger.
- Me too.
This is all I've got, boss.
Tie them two by two.
(HOWLING)
What are we gonna do now, boss?
I gotta talk to Ramjee.
Big Ben calling Ramjee.
Do you read me?
Ramjee, do you read me?
Out of range again.
George, you see that dome?
I'm gonna go up there
to get range.
Got to talk to
Ramjee about this.
I'm leaving you in charge.
You watch these people.
Okay, now, you people.
You behave, nobody gets hurt.
(CHUCKLES)
(GUNSHOT)
(WHIMPERING)
Get the gun!
Hey, you mustn't do that.
My boss will kill you!
- Got it.
- Okay, let's go.
- Get in.
- What do you mean, "Get in"?
Move it, man.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Mister, come with us.
I wanna come too.
He's gonna kill me.
You, give me first gear.
Hurry.
I knew it, I knew it.
I told you we're low on gas.
Let's get out of here.
Move your ass, man.
BEN: What a day.
Game rangers,
two soldiers and a woman.
What did you do with them?
I tied them up.
What the hell?
George!
Yes, boss?
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
(GUNSHOT)
Your turn!
(GUNSHOTS)
- Your turn!
- No, it's not!
- It is!
- It is! It is!
- No, it's not.
(GUNSHOT)
- It is!
- No, it's not!
Okay, damnit!
I'll get the bastard!
(PANTING)
(GIBBERISH)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(PANTING)
No, get up. Untie me.
(GUNSHOT)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
Come on.
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING)
(GASPING)
(GROWLING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Hey!
Oh, man.
Wait a minute.
He's not so crazy.
He knows what he's doing.
(FIRE CRACKLING)
He's making a firebreak.
Clever little bugger.
It'll burn out now.
That's it.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
They're your kids?
Yes, we passed them back there.
There's a tiny one
and the other one.
Yeah. That way.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
- Why are you crying?
- GEORGE: He lost his kids.
I told him where to find them.
So you have to disappear again.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Goodbye.
And thank you.
Goodbye and thank you.
Watch it! He's got a gun!
Out of my way!
I want you guys to
do that again.
- Do what?
- What you just did.
- What the hell for?
- It's a telescopic sight.
He can't hit a moving target.
- No!
- When I say go,
you run around like crazy.
All right?
Go!
Stand still, you bastards.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
Throw it away.
(INDISTINCT DIALOG)
Okay. Okay. Okay.
I'm your goddamn prisoner.
I don't want you.
You're a... You're a...
You're a shitty prisoner.
Xiri!
(ECHOING)
(SHOUTING, ECHOING)
(SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Don't shout
so many words at once.
Just tell me where you are.
(ECHOING)
What did you say?
(ECHOING, SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(BOTH SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(BARKING)
(SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(YELPING)
(LAUGHING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
- Okay, thank you.
- Okay, goodbye.
Bugger off to Cuba
and don't get lost.
See that hill over there?
You head straight for it,
and you'll find your jeep.
Goodbye.
Okay, out.
You drive the jeep.
- Where we going, boss?
- MAN: To my base.
How long will we get?
Maybe you'll get a year,
but this bastard's gonna sit
for a long time.
There are 12 spotter planes
and 9 helicopters searching the area
in a radius of 400 kilometers.
So we are covering
an area of 20,000...
(ENGINE BUZZING)
(LAUGHING)
- Isn't this where we kiss?
- Yes.
(SCREAMS)
Pull me up! Pull me up!
You're tearing my dress!
Let me down.
No, pull me up.
Don't bother.
I can't see!
Ahh!
Oh, boy.
Now can you do it right?
Daddy!
(LAUGHING)