It was a day like no other.
It was a day
I had always dreamed of...
a day I would never forget.
Will you marry this woman
and take her to your heart..
Forever devoted and forever young?
I will.
And will you marry this man
and take him to your heart...
forever devoted and forever young?
I will.
Would you now place
the ring on her finger?
I now declare you-
What a shame we had uninvited guests.
Eh! I'll have
what I came for this day!
Jack politely asked them to leave.
Kiss steel, bastard!
Jack!
Aha!
Get her!
Jack!
Hold tight! I'm coming!
His temper flared, but
he fought like a gentleman.
Jack! Jack!
Whoa!
Oh! Uh!
My one, true love had fought bravely...
but it wasn't enough.
There was only room for one more.
It was either my love or myself.
- You take it, my love.
- Never. Those maggots will not have you.
They will not have me for long.
I have consumption...
and will be dead
before the year is out.
You were gonna marry me
with consumption?
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't want to spoil things.
- Go!
- No!
Live to fight another day!
Whatever makes you happy.
With Jack, my happiness always came first.
I faced my fate alone.
The 10 turned to 20,
the 20 to 40.
Could this be the end of my freedom,
my salvation, my-
Hey! Gorgeous!
Hey! Hiya, Joanie!
♪♪
Wow!
What happened?
♪♪
“Was this the end of my freedom,
my salvation?”
My career?
♪♪
Heads up!
Oh!
♪♪
Whoo! Ah!
Gorgeous day.
Huh, gorgeous?
We got blue skies,
nice, warm water...
and a cold beer.
Honey, did you get any more Buds?
No. I just didn't have time today...
to ravage the Riviera
for your beer.
Tough day, huh?
Yeah, you could say
it was tough.
But then, when the going gets tough,
the tough-
I don't know what the tough do.
I don't know what the pirates do.
I don't know
what anybody does. Jack-
Oh, honey, I know.
I know, baby. I know.
Hey, I know.
But look out there.
What do you see?
- Bloomingdale's?
- No. Greece.
Greece?
Yeah. Mykonos, Lesbos,
Crete, ouzo, olive oil.
- Honey, we're going!
- Wait a minute.
You said we were gonna
go back to New York for a while.
Absolutely.
When the summer's over, we're goin'.
Aw, Jack! We've been on this boat
half a year now.
I need shore leave.
I promised Gloria...
I would finish that book
three months ago.
And I can't.
I don't know what happens next.
- - I thought you said you
wanted to sail around the world with me.
Well, I do, but-
but not all of it this week.
I mean, Jack,
this is just becoming a blur.
I mean,
exotic ports and great parties...
and spectacular sunsets.
- It's not enough.
- It's not enough?
You sound like somebody
who's got what they wanted...
and now they don't want
what they got.
- I want to do something serious.
- Serious? Oh, come on.
Aw, Jack. How much romance
can one woman take?
Joan Wilder?
- From your most devoted fan.
- Thank you.
“This afternoon we shall meet.
Awaiting the moment.”
What's this afternoon?
Well, it must be somebody
coming to the reception.
That's not till next Tuesday.
This is next Tuesday, Jack.
Just-Okay.
I thought you said
you were gonna get a car.
If I knew it was Tuesday,
it would've been here. I'm sorry.
Oh. That's all right.
What do you say we spin that roulette wheel
a few times while we're down there?
Sounds great.
Merci, monsieur. Au revoir.
- Merci. Bye.
- Jack. Jack?
- Yeah?
- She can't leave now.
- Why not?
- What do you mean, why not?
- Don't be ridiculous. Joan. Joan, darling.
- Oh, my God.
I am your biggest fan!
I have read all your books.
Well, thank you very much.
I'm so happy to see you!
- This is my publisher, Gloria Horne.
- Oh, your publisher.
- And-And this is-
- Oh, you are Mr. Wilder?
- No. I'm Mr. Colton. Jack Colton.
- What do you do, Mr. Colton?
- Casino work.
- Casino work?
Yeah. I think I'll go downstairs
and punch in. Excuse me.
- Excuse me one second.
- But, Jack?
I'll be back.
I've got to have a drink.
Literary functions
are not exactly Jack's speed.
The guy's favorite author is the man
who wrote “Pull tab to open.”
I am his favorite author.
You're telling me it's
none of my business?
Let me tell you something. Jack is not
the marrying kind. I am worried about you.
You're the girl who never gets a book
back late to the library.
You are three months
past your deadline.
Now, what gives with you?
Un scotch double.
My heart just isn't in it.
I mean-Romance just doesn't
seem real to me anymore.
Real? You don't write “real.”
You write about people
that sail off into the goddamn sunset.
What about the next day
when the sun comes up?
There is no next day.
That's why it's a romance.
You've got to stop confusing real life
with a romantic novel.
Joanie, just finish it.
I can't. I mean, after 17 books...
I don't know
how it ends anymore.
Then permit me to tell you.
It doesn't end.
It only begins anew
when you journey down the Nile with me.
- Have you got the right woman?
- No.
My name is Omar Khalif a...
and I've traveled 1,000 miles
to tell you I need you.
- You sent me the flowers.
- They pale by your beauty.
Oh, marry him.
- I read about you.
- Yes, I know. Time magazine.
I'm afraid the Western press
cannot understand the spirit of my vision.
You are a writer.
You can understand.
So, Joan Wilder,
you must come and write my story.
I only write romance novels.
Yes, and you haven't finished
the one you're working on right now.
You are a gifted storyteller.
You create heroes
in a world of cynics.
Journey down the Nile with me...
and I'll give you a chance
to record history.
- Come. We must leave today.
- Joanie!
In just four nights,
I will become emperor...
and you will have
the exclusive story.
They have emperors on the Nile?
They do now.
Oh, shit.
♪♪
So, now what are we celebrating?
- The Nile.
- Oh, the Nile.
We've been invited to Africa.
Uh, Jack Colton, Omar Khalif a.
How do you do?
He's, uh, asked me-me-
to write his story.
It's just what
I've always wanted to do.
And now Joan's work will receive
the serious attention that it deserves.
And this will be her
biggest accomplishment-my biography.
What's so important down there
that you have to write the book now?
- Mr. Khalif a has-
- “Omar.” Please.
Omar has been chosen
to unite the tribes of the Nile...
and to end the internal strife
that has bloodied his land.
He will carry on the work
of the Great Redeemer, who has disappeared.
- You have listened very well.
- You got all that in 20 minutes?
As a friend of Miss Wilder's,
you are very welcome to be my guest also.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
Could I talk to you
for a minute, please?
I thought you wanted
to go to New York.
- That's all changed.
- That fast, huh?
But, Jack, to write a biography-
I mean, something important, something
real-This is what I've been looking for.
You don't think this is a little bit
over your head, Joan?
I think it's a great chance.
You got your heart
set on it, huh?
Mine's set on Greece.
So, when are you gonna leave?
Tonight. Um,
he has a private jet, and-
Oh, he's got a private jet.
Well, what the hell.
We had a good run, didn't we?
Oh, Jack, come on. This is just
five or four weeks of research.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe we need a break.
Yeah, it's-it's been
kind of tough lately.
Yeah.
When the going gets tough,
the, uh, tough go to Greece.
Well, I'll write you.
Where?
Yeah. Where?
I think I'll go down and give
that roulette wheel one more chance.
You take care of yourself.
And you stay out of trouble.
Look out for her, will you?
I can offer you this comfort-
She leaves you for a higher purpose.
Yeah.
Free Al-Jawhara!
Don't be frightened.
You know, a man of vision
has many enemies...
and my destiny
is to outsmart them.
You see?
Like it?
It's okay.
Well, sweetheart,
I guess it's just you and me.
Goddamn it.
She was the best time I ever had.
Don't cry, scumbag.
I'll keep ya company.
Cartagena, Colombia!
- Long time, no-Oh, shit!
- Go ahead!
Go ahead! Give me a reason.
Make my year.
Go easy with the gun.
All right, buddy? Easy.
Did you miss me?
I missed you.
You're all I thought about for six months.
They threw me in a jail-
filled with rejects
from the communicable disease ward.
Every wacko, drippy...
open-sored lowlife
was in that joint-
all of them wantin' to hire on
as my proctologist.
And rats! Rats!
I'm full of rat bites.
Ten weeks of rabies shots this long.
And all I thought of was you, Colton!
- Just you!
- I'm-I'm flattered, pal.
And I'm-I'm sorry you had
such a tough time.
Uh, how about a hundred bucks?
Hundred bucks? I'll give you
a one-way ticket to harp land.
- No more jokes! What'd you do with it?
- What are you talking about?
The stone, moron!
I'm cocked here.
Listen, listen! Let's talk about this
like gentlemen, all right?
Gentlemen? Did I tell ya
I got malaria in the jail?
Every time I shake-
I shake like this.
You know what happens
if I shake my trigger finger?
And I feel an attack
comin' on right now.
You know what happens
if that happens?
You know what'll happen? It's the
end of Mr. Lucky. That's the end of-
Holy shit!
- Holy shit!
- Quiet!
Next time,
you'll not be so lucky.
- I am Tarak. You must come with me now.
- What the hell are you?
- Omar steal our jewel-Al-Jawhara.
- Jewel?
You were invited with the woman.
You can get into Omar's palace.
My people cannot.
What people? What the hell you
talkin' about? I don't know who you are.
- You must come to help me find the jewel!
- What jewel?
The Jewel of the Nile-our
most priceless jewel.
Oh, that jewel.
Omar has stolen my people's jewel,
Omar is a very bad man.
That scum!
I spit on him. Ptoo!
Jack, buddy. Let's help this nice man
get his jewel back.
Yes, yes.
I don't know where you're
from or what you're on...
but I'm sailing my boat tonight.
No! You must come to help find the
jewel now-before Omar kill many people.
As long as Omar have the jewel,
nothing can stop him.
Look, I'm going on the boat.
You guys can do what you want.
The boat blew up.
My boat blew up.
The boat blew up!
Everything's gone.
Who are you-the Prince of Darkness?
Don't you got any friends?
This is the work of Omar.
Omar blew up my boat, huh?
Your woman is in danger too.
I will take you to him.
- I'm coming too!
- The hell you are!
Look, you owe me, Colton.
So wherever you're goin',
I'm goin'.
- Where we goin'?
- Africa.
Do you recognize my home?
- I wrote this!
- Yes, in The Return of the King.
I had the same uniforms designed.
♪♪
Hello.
Hi.
- Is all this yours?
- It belongs to the country, to my people.
Oh.
Oh!
Why point out the negative?
In three nights, in the city of Kadir,
the moon will be full...
and all my people
will unite behind me in peace.
And none of this will be necessary.
- Now let me show you my humble house.
- Thank you.
Omar! Omar!
I'm really blessed.
My people love me.
It's, like-
Yes, they seem very en-enthusiastic.
Oh. This is a good shot for you-
the little boy
holding up my picture.
Oh, yeah. That's wonderful.
My humble house.
You must forgive us.
We are a poor people.
Everything you need,
they will bring to you.
Oh, thank you.
In my country, only
strangers say thank you.
Family and friends have no need.
- What was that?
- Cats.
- Come.
- Oh.
I have a cat.
- I hope this is satisfactory.
- Oh.
Oh, yes. This is okay.
Uh, fine.
Here you will write
your masterpiece.
Ah. I have a few questions.
I see the writer is already at work.
Good.
Explore your new world.
Feel free to go anywhere
and see anything...
talk to anyone.
I am glad you're here, Joan.
Together, we'll make history.
It's like a fishbowl!
Why do these third world cesspools
always gotta be so hot?
Will you tell me that?
Hey. Where the hell you goin'?
Holy shit!
♪♪
Well, Colton, looks like
we've hitched our wagon to a star.
♪♪
Stop that! Stop it!
Excuse me.
Um, what does this mean?
- Al-Jawhara.
- Al-Jawhara?
- Do you speak English?
- “Give back the jewel.”
Give back the jewel?
Yeah.
Hey! You can't do that! I'm a professional!
We'll see about that.
If you don't tell me
what the hell is going on here...
I am going to be on the first plane
back to New York.
It's impossible.
Tomorrow we journey to Kadir.
You must be there.
It will be
your most important chapter.
I can't write this book
if you keep secrets from me.
- What secrets?
- Al-Jawhara?
What is the jewel?
The jewel is a legend.
I am real.
Do not be distracted
from your mission, Joan Wilder.
Make yourself comfortable.
You'll stay with me
until our book is done.
You can't keep me here.
Go. You are free to leave.
Only the worst kind of fool
would attempt our desert alone.
♪♪
I gotta get off this camel.
He's breakin' my ass.
Colton. I can't take it.
I can't. No! No!
Not the left one!
Oh, shit!
Camp's comin' up. The left one!
♪♪
Come! You are welcome!
We have food!
We have drink!
You got a toilet?
♪♪
So, how big is this jewel?
Very, very big. Very big. Very, very big.
Very big. Very big.
Is it as big as this orange?
It's as big as an orange.
The jewel is the heart
of our people.
Omar steals
the heart of our people.
- Omar is thief!
- Omar is very bad man.
Before Omar steal our jewel,
everything good.
Now everything is shit!
Omar is thief!
You help us find the jewel...
and we give you great reward.
But if you lie to us, you die!
But now we dance!
Yallah! Yallah! Yallah!
Whoa!
♪♪
Look at these guys, Colton.
No sheep is safe tonight.
♪♪
We split it
right down the middle, Colton.
- Fifty-fifty.
- What are you talking about?
Don't play stupid with me, partner.
The jewel!
And don't you even think
of messin' with me.
Oh! What's that I hear-
a heart breakin'? You sap!
Better keep your mind
on business, Romeo.
You'll wind up getting yourself killed
over some broad who dumped you.
Jewels! Ha!
Oh, Omar. Ooh!
I want you lot to be careful!
Careful. See that word “Fragile”
on the side?
It means don't drop-
What did I just say?
I might love your country.
I might love your culture.
I might even love your people.
That means I love you.
But you drop another one of those boxes,
I'll smash your bloody face in!
You tell Omar, right-Omar-
that his special-effects wizard
has arrived.
Come on then.
War plans.
Oh, my God.
What is he up to?
Wait till Time magazine sees this.
You bastard!
You burnt my hand!
I didn't say it wouldn't burn.
I said it wouldn't hurt!
Look, there's no blistering. No blistering.
I've done it hundreds of times on stage.
Look, this is not
a cheap theatrical stunt.
It's a miracle.
My people have to believe it!
Omar, trust me.
Trust what I've got to say.
Look, if I can make gods
out of rock-and-roll stars...
imagine what I can do for you.
For your information,
I am not a rock-and-roll star.
The people must believe
I have the same powers as the Jewel.
Come. I want to see him now.
If it weren't for the Jewel,
I'd have led my people to power long ago.
You Westerners understand nothing.
The Jewel represents
the spiritual world of my people.
Unless I can convince them
I am their spiritual leader...
they will never follow me
into battle.
That is why you are here.
Tell me how it's done, magician.
It's not magic trick. It's miracle.
I am losing patience with you!
But you cannot kill me.
Even you are superstitious.
- Al-Jawhara lives.
- Al-Jawhara?
Two nights from now, it will not matter.
Yallah!
Oh, no.
A woman?
Most unexpected.
I gotta get outta here.
I gotta stop Omar.
Did you bring an army?
What? No. I'm ju-
I'm just Joan Wilder.
Just-Joan Wilder,
I'm Al-Jawhara.
Al-Jawhara?
The Jewel of the Nile.
I don't understand.
You're the Jewel?
Eh, for the moment.
In two nights,
at the holy city of Kadir...
Omar will proclaim himself emperor.
Without me to oppose him, he'll
march across North Africa like a madman.
- But the world
will see me as the savior of my people.
No, it won't.
The world won't believe you.
I've been in your office,
and I've seen your vision.
- I'm gonna write the truth about you!
- The truth?
If I wanted the truth,
I would have hired 60 Minutes.
What do you know about truth?
You fantasize everything.
Why do you think
I brought you here?
You stay here, and you write
what I tell you to write.
You think no one knows I'm here?
Oh, yes. Jack.
I forgot to tell you.
Jack is dead.
Don't be ridiculous.
Jack would never die without telling me.
Nevertheless, he is dead.
You look pale, Miss Wilder.
I'll send you my personal physician.
It can't be true.
This Jack, he is friend for you?
Yes.
He is my best friend.
I- I don't see shit.
We must stop here.
It is dangerous for Sufis
to enter Omar's city.
Now, wait a minute.
This guy's already tried to kill me once.
You are guest of Omar.
Find for us the Jewel.
Accept your destiny.
Destiny, my ass.
When you hook up with a bunch of Jujubes,
you see what happens?
Just take your lead from me,
and we'll be fine.
What are we gonna do,
walk right through the center of town?
I'm gonna put you up a
camel's ass for openers.
I think I might like it.
What are you doing?
In one of my books-
Angelina's Savage Secret-
she used her nail file to cut the mortar
away from the window bars.
How long did this take?
Two pages.
Eh, but it's not the bars that
make the prison. It is the desert.
So I'll travel at night.
I don't care. I have to stop Omar.
I gotta get out of here
if I'm gonna write the truth about him.
I have to get to Kadir.
Wait a minute.
You're the one that has to get to Kadir.
You're the only one that can stop Omar.
You have to go with me.
Ah. Hmm.
Maybe you are the one.
I accept.
We are sworn, Just-Joan.
- Right. But it's just Joan.
- Right. Just-Joan.
Right. We just have
to get out this window.
Please. Please.
Please.
- Magic.
- Dry rot.
I bet you could pick up
a swell three-bedroom townhouse here...
for about five or six dollars.
Hiya, guys.
My name is Colton.
I've been invited by your Omar.
I'm here to see Joan Wilder.
Rachid!
Hey, Rachid, how are you?
Good to see you again.
Joan Wilder does not
want to see you.
Well, now, Rachid,
I don't think you understand.
Uh, we're here on official business.
Now, this is Mr., uh, Fatush
from the US. Embassy.
He's got something very important
to talk to all you guys about.
Yeah. Look, we don't want to create
an international incident here.
After all, she is
an American citizen.
If you'll just let us see her-
no paperwork.
Mum's the word.
Everything will be-
Guys, no sweat. We'll catch
you next time we're in town.
- Take it easy.
- Say hello to her for us.
You know what they say-Once they've
had a holy man, they never go back.
Quickly, Just-Joan!
Are you sure you know
where you're going?
I heard those guys can go for hours
without comin' up for air.
Ease up, will you? There's gotta be
another way in here some place.
I can't wait for another smooth move
from Dr. Doom.
How about you and me
at the back door in pussycat suits?
When they come
with the saucer of milk-
- How about you taking it in the ear?
- Ooh! Very-
Look, pal, if it wasn't for me,
you wouldn't be onto this.
Subsequently, I should shoot you
the first chance I get.
Jack! You're alive!
Kind of going outta
your way to duck me, aren't you?
- You bastard!
- Just-Joan!
Oh! Jack!
I thought I'd never see you again.
They told me you were dead,
and I believed them!
- I never wanna feel that way again!
- Does this mean you apologize?
I feel like I'm back in eighth grade here.
What is this-
The Young and the Stupid?
What the hell is he doing here?
Don't get cagey with me, sweetheart.
I'm onto it.
I know how you two operate.
I'll get in there
with or without you dinks!
Hey, look, guys.
Lighten up, will you?
I only said hello
to an old girlfriend here.
Just-Joan! We need to go!
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Who's this guy?
- He's a friend.
- You made friends in there?
- Okay, let's go. Come on.
- Wait, wait. He's coming with us.
Don't start with me! All right? I've come
halfway across Africa to rescue you.
Rescue me?
I was doin' fine without you!
I am guide. I can help you.
- I don't need a guide! I need a miracle!
- Jack, he's coming with us.
All right! But if we get out of this alive,
I'm gonna kill you!
Let's go. Come on.
Al-Jawhara!
- Who are you?
- Is this where Al Jolson's buried?
Who the hell are you?
Hey! Don't provoke
me, pal' I had a tough day.
You know how hot it is here?
It's 120 degrees in the shade.
I'm like this with Weinberger.
We'll be all over you like a cheap suit.
Yallah!
Let me in!
Let me in! Oh!
Holy shit!
And shove me in it!
Oh, no! Over the wall!
Uh!
Ooh! Ooh!
Oh! Excuse me. Excuse me.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Come on. Move it! Oy! Ow! Oh, no! No!
Okay, fly boy, your estimated
time of departure's right now!
- What are you doing?
- I'm not doing anything!
- Well, do something!
- All right! I'm trying!
I mean, this isn't Space Invaders!
Jack! The wall!
Aw, no!
It is Space Invaders.
Wahoo! That'll show 'em!
All right! Yeah!
Oh, shit Jack.
Let's get outta here.
This is gonna be tight!
This is my first time in airplane.
- Oh. Uh-
- How do you stop this thing?
Sorry.
- Do you know where you're going?
- Give me a break, will ya?
Al-Jawhara!
- Your friend steal the Jewel!
- What?
- You-You are liar to me!
- No!
I come back, and you are dead!
Colton, you thieving bastard!
You ain't stiffin' me again!
I promise you!
I'll feed you to the maggots!
I'll... Al-Jawhara! - Al-Jawhara!
Al-Jawhara!
Oh, great!
We're out of quarters.
Well-Try that one there.
Now what? Damn it!
Yes!
- Yes!
- Hey, that's not bad for your first time.
Come on. We got 'im.
We got 'im.
Colton, you ain't gettin' away.
♪♪
Where the hell's the horn?
Get outta here!
Get outta the way! Come on!
Sandstorm!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
What are you gonna do?
Either save us or kill us.
Hang on!
No!
- Now you are dead.
- Don't cut off my head! Please!
- You stole our Jewel.
- No! It wasn't me! It was the mook!
He's constantly screwing me!
I swear to God on my eyes!
I never seen that jewel!
No, wait! No, wait, wait!
Wait! Wait! wait!
You need me.
- I can help you find him.
- You are his friend.
No! No, no! Friend?
Stop saying that.
Friends don't stab
each other in the back.
Come on, look.
Look, we-we'll team up.
We'll find the mook,
get 'im good.
He knows that I will not be denied.
Colton's future is bleak.
Very bleak!
Any idea where we are?
Well, the best
I can figure out...
is, if we head due east,
we should make it to the border.
But-Is that the way to Kadir?
Laa. Kadir is in the west,
over that mountain.
The best of luck to you, pal.
Joan, come on. Let's get going.
Jack, we have to take him to Kadir.
What are you talking about?
We got him out like you said.
The guy's gonna be fine.
Now come on.
We swore an oath, Just-Joan and I.
We go to Kadir.
What is it with you? Geez!
I mean, everything's always
got to be your way?
- This is just like the goddamn boat!
- What do you mean, my way?
It wasn't my idea
to spend six months on your boat!
- Oh! Debate good. I enjoy.
- Let me tell you what I put up with.
We're moored
off the Canary Islands, right?
Midnight-sound asleep-
three crazed Joan Wilder fans...
decide they want the anchor
of the Angelina for a souvenir!
- We were drifting for days! And what
about the other time... Stop. I'm sorry.
It's time for Just-Joan.
- Remember the Costa Del Sol, Jack?
- Aw, come on.
He's got to meet me at the governor's
for a formal dinner.
And you show up with the entire
Italian national basketball team!
- Hey, they were hungry.
- This is exactly what I'm talking about.
I just wish sometimes
you could think about me.
Oh! Oh, and I suppose you were thinking all
about me when you took off with Omar, huh?
- Did I tell you he blew up my boat?
- Our boat.
- Oh. Now it's our boat.
- Is good. Good debate.
Is equal. No winners.
Just-Joan, we must hurry.
No, wait. What do you mean
he blew up our boat?
Just tell me one thing.
Why are you risking your life for this guy?
I made a commitment.
I can't break it.
Okay.
Okay, fine.
I'm gonna tell you the truth.
I didn't come here for you anyway.
No. I'm onto something big.
A jewel-the Jewel of the Nile.
Come with us.
I am Jawhara.
Uh, that means “Joe.”
Thanks, Joe, but no thanks.
I wouldn't want her
to break her commitment.
Aw, Jack.
I mean, come on.
That's for the Angelina.
I still owe you for Joan.
Oh, no. Oh, God.
Please, let me get outta this alive.
I swear to God.
I'll be a good boy from tomorrow on.
Al-Jawhara!
But, tonight, I gotta kill Colton.
Joan Wilder!
Val/ah! Val/ah!
Why you didn't want
to tell your friend about me?
Oh, I know him.
He'd go halfway around the world
for a great party...
but he wouldn't go across town
for a noble cause.
- People can surprise you.
- No. He's just Jack. He'll never change.
Like, uh-Like a stone.
It's always a stone.
Open your hand.
Change is not always visible.
All right!
Let's show some hustle!
- What?
- Your buddy, Omar!
What is it?
He can't live without you?
- Are we jogging?
- We are jogging!
Greece is looking better and better.
Uh-huh.
Aw, shit.
Will you just tell me why the hell
this guy wants you so bad?
- Hey, Joe, where you goin'?
- Uh, this way.
You gotta be kidding.
He probably knows the mountains
better than you, Jack.
Joan, will you give me a break?
Will ya?
America-democracy.
We vote, huh?
Stop! Stop!
It's him!
Hurry up! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on!
Get down! Get down!
- It's a black day for democracy.
- Do not worry.
I'm sure it's not my destiny
to die on this mountain.
- What about us?
- That's another ball game.
Rachid!
Joan Wilder,
I wish no harm to you.
I'm your friend, your fan.
Please surrender.
What'd you do for this guy Omar
you never did for me?
Bloody bitch.
Oh, shit! Look out!
Hey, Omar!
Eat rock shit!
Let's go over there.
I got something.
Nubians.
I was hoping to avoid them.
Sell any books here?
Main man. Hey! My man!
- What are you so happy about?
- Just keep smiling.
Maybe they'll think
we're from National Geographic.
Hey, how you doing, you guys?
How you doing?
He says it's many days long trip
over high mountains.
And he wishes us
a very pleasant journey.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
- You're all right. Thank you, guys.
- Thank you. Excuse us.
Catch you next time, all right?
Good-bye.
Come on, Jack.
Ah, Mr. Jack, Just-Joan.
The chief's son-
He wishes to make a blessing
for your marriage and your children.
We're not married.
He says,
because you are not married...
that, uh, his son
wishes to court you.
- I just-
- No, that's, uh-
That's very nice, but the lady is, uh-
She's with me.
He says that because
there is more than one suitor...
that you must wrestle his son.
I gotta wrestle his son?
Uh-huh.
How you doing?
Okay. This one,
I think I can handle.
Okay.
No?
Hyacinthe!
Hey, but, guys, this is cuckoo
Wait a minute, guys.
Let's talk this over like gentlemen,
all right? Come on!
All right! You guys are for me, huh?
Yeah, me. All right.
Do me a favor. Tell him we lived together
for six months. Aw, shit.
All right. All right.
What are the rules?
- Right.
- Yeah!
- Oh! Oh!
- I'm really sorry about that.
Oh, no! Not the left one!
- Jack!
- No pain, no gain.
Oh, let me go!
No! No!
- Can we talk about this?
- Stop it!
We have to do something!
I am doing something.
Oh!
Joe, he's-
No!
Ay!
Yeah!
Yea!
Aha! Yeah!
That was great!
Great, huh?
I could have gotten killed!
♪♪
- Yeah!
This is the marriage dance.
In this tribe, the women-
They choose the men.
And then according
to the custom...
they will be together
for the rest of their lives.
- They get all that from one dance?
- Eh-heh.
I think it's beautiful.
Ralph, if you want to be one of us...
take off your shoes and socks.
If you want to be one of us, you must see
with the eyes of your heart...
- not with the eyes of your head.
- Gotcha, yeah.
Your heart will never
give you fear or pain...
if you know our way.
- Ralph.
- Uh, no, thanks, pal.
- Keep your friggin' jewel. No! Hey! Hey!
- Are you afraid?
Well, I just had my feet resoled.
What is the worst
that can happen to you?
I could wind up
a Chicken McNugget.
What is the best
that could happen to you?
I could get through this
and find the jewel.
It's your choice. Look down.
Hot coals! Hot coals!
I did it! I did it!
I'm one of us!
Ya ya ya ya!
♪♪
All right! Yeah!
Yeah!
Your fears-
They make you foolish.
Go to her, Jack.
I'm sorry I got people
shooting at you again, Jack.
Are you kidding? We're the perfect couple
when we got people shootin' at us.
It's just the slow times
I'm not too good at.
I guess I just expect too much.
Maybe we both expect too much.
Oh, boy.
Thank you for coming
to Kadir with me.
This valley is gift of the Nile.
I've been away
from here too long.
I'm getting to like this guy Joe.
He's growing on me.
What do you say we cut him in
on this jewel if we ever find it?
Jack, uh... we have the Jewel.
What are you talking about?
Where?
Well, there.
What, Joe's got the jewel?
No. Joe is the Jewel.
Joe is the Jewel of the Nile?
He's a-a holy man.
That's his religious title.
Joe's the Jewel.
Why didn't you tell me the truth?
Why'd you keep it from me?
Because I thought, if you knew,
you wouldn't come with us.
Maybe I would've surprised you.
I think I've come through once or twice,
if I remember right.
I'm sorry. You're right.
You come through all the time.
It's funny.
I really thought we had a chance.
Ah! Look, Just-Joan-
the train to Kadir.
Come on, Jack.
Inshallah, we'll be there tonight.
- What a lot of people!
- Yes, those are pilgrims.
- They are going to see the false redeemer.
- Omar again, huh?
Well, we'll see about that.
Oh, shit.
Val/ah! Val/ah!
What are you doing?
Come on.
Jump!
No!
- Jack!
- Hey.
Jack!
Hang on! Hang on, Joan!
Jack, watch out!
It's-Aah!
Al-Jawhara.
Al-Jawhara!
“Olly!” What?
Olly! Olly! Olly! Olly!
Guys, wait up! Come on, Humphrey.
Go! Go! Go! Olly! Olly!
Do something!
What do you want me to do?
Joan Wilder!
SN
Colton!
Hah!
Your ass is grass,
and I'm a lawn mower, Colton!
Colton! I'll get you, Colton!
I'm onto you!
Colton!
Colton.
Yea! All right! Yeah!
All right, let's go.
Come on. Let's get outta here.
Just-Joan, you're great-
Welcome, welcome.
I don't usually travel by train...
but I had a small accident
with my helicopter.
May we reach Kadir in time.
Inshallah.
Once we get inside,
we must find the entrance to the catacombs,
Take home a T-shirt!
T-shirts! Buy T-shirts.
Get outta here.
Give me the T-shirt.
I'll buy it. I'll buy it.
Get outta here, will ya?
You know,
I really admire your loyalty to each other.
And I'm going to give you a chance
to be together to the very end.
Well, not exactly. One
will watch the other die.
But which one?
Rachid.
Is that the goat blood?
Yes.
Very popular with the inhabitants
of these catacombs,
- Rats.
- Yes. And they will eat...
until they get the very last drop.
But don't worry, Mr. Colton.
You won't be alone.
Rachid is now placing acid..
That will eat through
Miss Wilder's rope.
What kind of sick pervert would go
to this trouble? Why don't you shoot us?
Jack!
I mean, what kind of
demented psychopath...
- would even think of this?
- The Savage Secret.
- What?
- It was my biggest seller.
Oh.
Think about this pit
as your last adventure, Joan Wilder.
My people await me. Rachid!
What you talkin' about? I'm used
to workin' with professional people.
You tell His Highness
the show starts with him or without him.
Goddamn beanie convention.
We'll end up going home with a rug.
The entrance.
Give me a red
to the yellow and cue!
♪♪
I said give me
a red gel down there!
And cue!
For God's sake, cue!
♪♪
Build it. Build it softly. Build it-
And give me some smoke.
That's good. That's good.
That's very good. Now bring it up.
Bring it up slowly.
Omar! Omar!
♪♪
- Hey, hey, hey!
- There are many rooms and many ways.
You, you go this way.
And you, you go this way.
And we, we go this way.
Oh, ooh! What a stench in this place.
- What looks good, amigo?
- Uh, you go from this way.
And, uh, I go this way.
All right.
Froot Loop.
- So how'd they get out?
- What?
In The Savage Secret,
how'd they get out?
Oh. Uh...
Jessie had a knife
hidden in his boot.
You wouldn't happen
to have a knife, would you?
I'm not even wearing underwear.
Great.
- Aah! Jack!
- No! No!
We were good together,
weren't we, Joan Wilder?
The best.
- And we're gonna make it.
- Yeah.
Oh, God, I love you, lady.
I love you, Jack.
- Will you marry me?
- Yes!
Because I don't ever want you
leaving me again.
You're not just saying that
because this is it, are you?
I'm saying it because
I'm not afraid to say it anymore.
So where you wanna go
on our honeymoon?
Omar! Omar!
Rats! Get out of here.
It's a goddamn rat farm. Go on!
Ralph! Ralph,
get us out of here, will ya?
Oh! And there's
the biggest rat of all.
Ooh, Colton, look at you, you-
You don't know how many nights
I dreamed of this very thing...
- except your flesh was torn off your body.
- Please, just help us down.
Jack, the rope!
Well, well, well, Colton.
I think this calls for a renegotiation.
Don't you, Tarzan? Huh?
This looks a little bit more like 70-30
or maybe even 80-20.
Ralph, will you get the rats off my rope!
I don't go near rats, buddy.
Ralph, do not be afraid.
Remember the Sufi way.
See with your heart.
My heart sees rats, pop.
Don't let this garb fool you.
Come on, Colton,
where's the jewel?
Ralph, I am the Jewel-
the Jewel of the Nile.
Yeah, and I'm a kumquat
from Queens.
- Pipe down, towel head!
- Come on, Ralph!
Take the ladder
and put it over the well.
- Please, please, don't let us die.
- That's a good idea, legs.
I ain't gonna let you die,
but I ain't movin' no damn ladder...
until you two
come across with the rock.
Lookin' more like 90-10,
huh, kumquat?
Uh, did you get the ladder
all right, buddy?
- Jack, help me unlock the Jewel.
- The Jewel?
You mean you weren't shittin' me?
That guy really is the Jewel?
Come on. We still got time
to stop Omar! Let's go.
Ralph, that is not the Sufi way.
I don't know
what got into me, Jewels.
Every time I'm around this guy,
he makes me crazy.
Aw, come on.
Tell him to cut me down, Jewels.
Come on. Come on, huh?
Omar! Omar!
Joan Wilder!
Don't fuck around with the equipment!
Bloody woman!
Joan Wilder!
- Get them! Go!
- Here they come, Jack.
Oh, my God. Look at this.
Looks like Our Lady of Mount Carmel
school yard.
H-Hold it!
Excuse me. Pardon me.
Pardon me. Comin' through.
Ho, ho, ho. Oh, Rachid.
How you doin'?
Let's talk this over
before you butcher me alive.
What are you gettin'
so steamed about?
Look at that. It worked.
Jawhara!
Al-Jawhara!
Get over the wall!
Go on! Come on!
Get going! Get going!
Keep going!
I knew we'd hook up again, Colton!
Get it!
I swear to God!
My right hand to God! Come on!
I am dead, Miss Wilder.
All that will be written for Omar
is an epitaph.
But I will not be alone.
Who is going
to save you now, hmm?
Who?
Well, you got your story.
I got a lot more than that.
You are married.
♪♪
Always a bridesmaid,
never the bride.
As usual,
it's zilch for poor Ralphie.
You are Sufi.
Keep it always.
Aw, guys!
Ahh.
Sufis rule!
♪♪